JOHN BALORAN

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

CONTACT

PHONE 289-946-2224

EMAIL jdbalora@gmail.com

LINKS

www.johnbaloran.com

www.linkedin.com/in/johnbaloran

www.github.com/johnBaloran

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React

Javascript

HTML5

CSS3

SASS

Data Structures and Algorithms

API Integration

Responsive Design

Git, Github

Paired Programming

Firebase

SOFT SKILLS

Complex Problem Solving

Communication

Customer Service

Time Management

Adaptability

PROFILE

Dedicated Front-End Developer with experience building applications using React, Javascript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3, Firebase, API integrations and other front end technologies. I have a passion for writing clean, dry, and structured code to build accessible and responsive web applications. My experience as a Kinesiology student has given me a strong ability to think outside the box and approach problems from new angles, by using my knowledge of nutrition and exercise to communicate effectively in school projects. Now, I am excited to use these skills as well as my technical skills in my new career.

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE BOOTCAMP

JUNO COLLEGE | Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

YORK UNIVERSITY | Sept 2015 - Jun 2020

PROJECTS

SMOOTH LANDING

REPO | LIVE

React-Router / API Integration / Firebase / Mob Programming / CSS3 / HTML5

A single page web application that creates landing pages for clients in less than 5 minutes. Clients are able to copy and paste generated code for selected landing page. Working with the Unsplash API, clients are able to choose from a variety of background images. All data is stored in a firebase database for future use.

TODO-TODAY

REPO | LIVE

React / Firebase / CSS3 / HTML5

A classic CRUD todo app that organizes a list of tasks in order of priority, that are needed to be completed in a time limit of 24 hours. Created using React Hooks and utilizes a form to add, delete, and edit user input while retrieving and returning data from Firebase database.

OUR PANTRY

REPO | LIVE

Javascript / API Integration / Paired Programming / SCSS/ CSS3 / HTML5

Multiple calls to two APIs pulls data that is calculated to render a list of recipe based on the user's available ingredients in their pantry or kitchen.

WORK EXPERIENCE

METRO

PRODUCE CLERK

Nov 2020 - PRESENT

- Preserved a welcoming environment by effectively communicating with at least 80 customers per shift, uncovered their needs and provided information on pricing, purchases and products
- Maintained inventories at 100% by anticipating customer demand and efficiently managing time.
- Received no customer complaints to date because of my personable and friendly manner as well as competence.

SOFINA

PACKAGING LINE OPERATOR

Jan 2017 - Aug 2020

- Exceeded yearly company production targets by 25 percent with recommendation and implementation of new strategies that promoted continuous improvement on the production line.
- Insured proper operation and assembly of line products and packaging. Keeping recorded log of all products produced during shift.